Welcome. In the last lecture, we created an AnimInstance class and in this lecture, we're
欢迎。在上一节课中，我们创建了一个AnimInstance类，而在这节课中，我们
going to rebuild our animation blueprint using the variables that we created. So first, I'm
使用我们创建的变量来重建我们的动画蓝图。所以首先，我要
going to open this ABB. Then inside of this AnimGraph, I'm going to right mouse button
我要打开这个神甫。然后在这个AnimGraph中，我要用鼠标右键
click and create a new state machine. And I'm going to rename this state machine to
单击并创建一个新的状态机。我将把这个状态机重命名为
ground local motion and double click to open it. And first I'm going to drag in this mm_idle,
地面局部运动，然后双击将其打开。首先，我要把这个空闲时间拖进来，
place it in here and I'm going to rename this one to idle. And I'm going to drag the pin
把它放在这里，我要把它重命名为IDLE。我要把大头针
from this entry point to this one. So this one here, this will be our idle animation
从这个切入点到这个切入点。所以这一个，这将是我们的闲置动画
and we can transition from our idle animation to another state. So I'm going to add a state
我们可以从闲置的动画转换到另一种状态。所以我要添加一个州
and I'm going to rename this one to walk run and double click to open this one. So in here,
我要把它重命名为Walk，Run，然后双击打开这个。所以在这里，
we simply need to drag in this plane space for this mm_walkrun and plug this pin to here.
我们只需要在这个平面空间中拖动这个mm_walkrun，并将这个插针插入到这里。
Now for this speed, we can simply use our ground speed. So I'm going to drag out this
现在对于这个速度，我们可以简单地使用我们的地面速度。所以我要把这件事拖下去
pin, get ground speed and connect it to here and go back to this ground local motion. So
别针，获得地面速度，并将其连接到这里，然后返回到这个地面局部运动。所以
for the transition condition, I'm going to double click to open it. We can simply use
对于过渡条件，我要双击将其打开。我们可以简单地使用
this BshouldMove. So drag it to here and connect this to here and I'm going to click compile
这辆车应该动起来。将其拖到此处并将其连接到此处，然后我将单击编译
and go back to ground local motion. So our walkrun can transition back to this idle.
然后回到地面局部运动。所以我们的徒步跑可以过渡回这个空闲的状态。
And for that, I'm going to drag out another pin, connect this one to idle and double click
为此，我将拖出另一个引脚，将此引脚连接到IDLE，然后双击
to open it. And the condition here, so I'm going to drag out this BshouldMove. So if
才能打开它。和这里的情况，所以我要把这一步拖下去。所以如果
this BshouldMove is false, I'm going to use this not boolean in here. If this is false,
这个BshoudMove是假的，我将在这里使用这个而不是布尔值。如果这是假的，
we should transition back to idle animation. All right, that's pretty much it. And I'm
我们应该回到闲置的动画中。好了，差不多就是这样了。而且我是
going to go back to this anim graph and I'm going to connect this ground local motion to
回到这张动画图表，我将把这个地面局部运动连接到
the final output, click compile. And now we should have our walkrun animation back. So
在最终输出中，单击编译。现在我们应该有我们的步行动画回来了。所以
go back to my left, I'm going to click play and just like that we have the basic local
回到我的左边，我要点击Play，这样我们就有了基本的本地
motion back. And now if I press the space bar, we still don't have our jump animation
回击动议。现在如果我按空格键，我们仍然没有跳跃动画
and that's what we're going to take care of next. So this is what I have so far. If you'd
这就是我们接下来要解决的问题。到目前为止，这就是我所拥有的。如果你愿意
like to catch up with me, you can pause the video now and give this a go. Welcome back.
想跟上我，你现在可以暂停视频，然后试一试。欢迎回来。
And the next thing that I'm going to do, I'm going to add in the jump animation. So go
接下来我要做的就是添加跳跃动画。那就去吧
back to this anim graph. And now I'm going to drag out a pin from this ground local motion
回到这个动画图表。现在我要从地面局部运动中拉出一根大头针
and I'm going to type in cache. So I'm going to cache this pose and I'm going to rename
我要在缓存中输入内容。所以我要缓存这个姿势，并将其重命名
this pose to cached ground local motion. And we're going to use this cache pose later.
此姿势到缓存的地面局部运动。我们稍后将使用这个缓存姿势。
All right. I'm going to right mouse button, click and create a new state machine. So this
好的。我要用鼠标右键点击并创建一个新的状态机。所以这就是
one I'm going to call it full body. And first thing I'm going to connect this full body
我把它叫做全身。我要做的第一件事就是把整个身体
to the final output result and double click to open it. The first state that we're going
到最终输出结果，然后双击将其打开。我们要去的第一个州
to go into, I'm going to call this ground local motion and double click to open it.
为了深入研究，我将把这称为地面局部运动，然后双击将其打开。
And in here I'm going to use the cache to post cache the ground local motion and connect
在这里，我将使用缓存来发布缓存地面局部运动并连接
it to the output. All right. Go back to full body. Now we have our ground local motion
把它传到输出端。好的。回到全身。现在我们有了地面局部运动
ready and we should be able to transition from this ground local motion to jump animation.
准备好了，我们应该能够从这个地面的局部运动过渡到跳跃动画。
So for jumping, there are actually three animations that we need to use. So if you double click
因此，对于跳跃，我们实际上需要使用三个动画。所以如果你双击
to open this mm underscore jump. So this is like the jump start and this fall loop. This
打开这个mm下划线跳跃。这就像是跳跃起跳和秋季回旋。这
is fall we are in the air and we also have this landing animation. So we all need to
秋天，我们在空中，我们也有这个着陆动画。所以我们都需要
make use of these three. All right. Go back to this animation blueprint. I'm going to
充分利用这三点。好的。回到这个动画蓝图。我这就做
first drag out this jump animation and I'm going to rename it to jump. Now instead of
首先拖出这个跳跃动画，我要将其重命名为JUMP。现在，不再是
directly drag out a pin from this ground local motion to jump, which can lead to a messy
直接从这个地面上拖出一根大头针来跳跃，这会导致乱七八糟的
graph quickly. Since many poses can transition to this jump animation in here, I'm going
快速绘制图表。因为很多姿势都可以过渡到这个跳跃动画，所以我要
to right mouse button click to add a state alias and I'm going to rename this alias to
要添加状态别名，请单击鼠标右键，我要将该别名重命名为
alias underscore from local motion. So what alias does is very similar as caching a pose
别名下划线来自局部运动。因此，Alias的作用与缓存姿势非常相似
inside of the anim graph. We can take the checkbox here to decide which state we want
动画图表的内部。我们可以选中此处的复选框来决定我们想要哪个州
to cache. So here I'm going to take this ground local motion and I'm going to drag out a transition
要缓存。所以在这里我要做的是地面局部运动，我要拖长一个过渡期
pin to this jump animation. So this is the same as dragging out a pin from this original
固定到此跳跃动画。所以这就相当于从这个原件上拖出一个大头针
state to be the jump. But in this way we should get a much cleaner graph. So for this transition
状态就是跳跃。但通过这种方式，我们应该会得到一个清晰得多的图表。所以对于这个过渡来说
condition, I'm going to click it and for this duration, I'm going to lower it down to 0.15.
条件，我会点击它，在这段时间里，我会把它降低到0.15。
For this mode, I'm going to change it to cubic. Then I'm going to double click to open this
对于此模式，我将其更改为立方体。然后我要双击打开它
transition condition. So in order for us to transition from ground locomotion to jump
过渡条件。所以为了让我们从地面运动过渡到跳跃
animation, there are two conditions that need to be true. So first I'm going to drag out
动画中，有两个条件需要为真。所以首先我要拖出
this is falling. So if this is falling is true and this airspeed is greater than 50
这是在下降。所以如果这个下降是真的，这个空速大于50
units. So if these conditions are true, then we can transition. So I'm going to use an
单位。因此，如果这些条件为真，那么我们就可以过渡。所以我将使用一个
end Boolean in here and connect this to here. Then go back to full body. All right. Next
在这里结束布尔运算，然后把这个连接到这里。然后回到全身。好的。下一首
thing our jump should be able to transition to this for loop. So I'm going to drag out
我们的跳跃应该能够过渡到这个for循环。所以我要拖着走
this animation and I'm going to rename this to for loop and I'm going to connect this
这个动画，我要把它重命名为for loop，我要把这个连接起来
to for loop for the duration here. I'm going to change it to 0.3 and change this mode to
To for循环的持续时间。我要将其更改为0.3，并将此模式更改为
cubic as well. And I'm also going to take this automatic rule. So once we are downplaying
也是立方的。我也要用这条自动规则。所以一旦我们轻描淡写
this animation, we should be able to transition to this for loop. And also there's another
这个动画，我们应该能够过渡到这个for循环。还有另一个
transition that we need to add in here. So our ground locomotion should be able to transition
我们需要在这里添加的过渡。所以我们的地面运动应该能够过渡到
directly to this for loop as well. This could happen when our character fall from a higher
直接连接到这个for循环。当我们的性格从更高的位置坠落时，这可能会发生
surface. So I'm going to click this transition rule, change this to cubic and double click
浮出水面。所以我要点击这个过渡规则，将其更改为立方体，然后双击
to open this transition rule. So I'm going to hold down control and left mouse button
以打开此过渡规则。所以我要按住Ctrl键和鼠标左键
click to drag out this is falling. Then hold down control again, drag out this airspeed.
单击以拖出This is Fall。然后再次按住Ctrl，拖出这个空速。
So if this is falling, it's true. And this airspeed is less than zero units. So if these
因此，如果这是在下降，那就是真的。而这个空速小于零个单位。所以如果这些
conditions are true, then we can enter the for loop state. So I'm going to connect this
条件为真，则可以进入for循环状态。所以我要把这个联系起来
and connect this to the final output and click compile in here. Go back to my full body.
并将其连接到最终输出，然后单击此处的编译。回到我的全身。
All right. That's the basic transition that we need to do for jumping. And next thing
好的。这是我们跳跃所需要做的基本转变。下一件事是
we need to take care of transitioning from for loop to this ground locomotion. And for
我们需要注意从FOR环路过渡到这个地面运动。而对于
that I'm going to use another state alias. I'm going to name this alias underscore from
我要用另一个国家化名。我将这个别名命名为下划线
jump. And here we need to take which state we want to cache. So it'll be jump and for
跳。在这里，我们需要获取要缓存的状态。所以这将是跳跃和为
loop. So we are catching two states in here. So both of these states should be able to
循环播放。所以我们在这里抓住了两个州。所以这两个州都应该能够
transition to a state and I'm going to call this state land and I'm going to double click
转换到一个州，我将把这个州称为土地，然后我将双击
to open this state. So I'm going to drag out this mm underscore land. And since this is
才能打开这个状态。所以我要画出这个mm下划线的土地。既然这是
an additive animation, we'll need to do this differently. So I'm going to right mouse button
一个加法动画，我们需要用不同的方式来处理。所以我要用鼠标右键
click and I'm going to use the cache the post, cache the ground locomotion and drag out a
点击，我将使用缓存帖子，缓存地面运动，并拖出一个
pin and use the function apply additive. And the additive animation will be this mm underscore
别针并使用功能涂抹添加剂。加法动画将是这个mm下划线
land and plug this into result. All right. And click compile, go back to full body. And
登陆并将这个插入到Result中。好的。然后点击编译，返回全身。和
next thing I'm going to take care of this transition rule. So click it, change its mode to cubic
下一件事，我将处理这个过渡规则。所以点击它，将其模式更改为立方体
and double click to open it and hold down control. I'm going to drag out this is falling.
然后双击将其打开并按住Ctrl键。我要拖下去，这是坠落。
So if this is falling is false. So use the not Boolean in here. Then we should enter the
因此，如果这是下降，那就是假的。所以在这里使用非布尔值。那么我们应该进入
land state. I'm going to move these two states to here. And last thing our land should be
土地之州。我要把这两个状态移到这里。我们的土地最不应该是
able to transition to this ground locomotion. So connected to here. So for the first condition,
能够过渡到这种地面运动。与这里的联系如此紧密。因此，对于第一个条件，
I'm going to take this automatic rule and change the duration to point three, change the mode
我将采用这条自动规则，将持续时间更改为点3，更改模式
to cubic. Once we are downplaying this animation, we should be able to enter the ground locomotion
转到立方。一旦我们淡化这个动画，我们应该能够进入地面运动
state or I'm going to drag out another pin and double click to open this new condition.
否则我将拖出另一个大头针，然后双击以打开此新条件。
If this B should move is true, then we should start transitioning right away. All right.
如果这个B应该移动是真的，那么我们应该立即开始过渡。好的。
I'm going to click compile, go back to full body. And that's pretty much it for this animation
我要点击编译，回到全身。这就是这部动画的主要内容
blueprint. I'm going to go back to my level and click play in here. You can see we have
蓝图。我要回到我的级别，然后在这里点击Play in。你可以看到我们有
our jump animation back and we can transition back to this ground locomotion state. Great.
我们的跳跃动画返回，我们可以转换回地面运动状态。太棒了。
Everything is working as usual. So these are all the states we need for rebuilding the
一切都像往常一样运转。因此，这些都是我们重建
animation blueprint. We are free to use this as a reference if you need. Now that we are
动画蓝图。如果您需要，我们可以自由地将其作为参考。现在我们是
using the animation blueprint we created, later when we want to add in the climb locomotion,
使用我们创建的动画蓝图，稍后当我们想要添加攀登运动时，
you'll be much easier for us to do so. All right. It's time for you to do the same and
对我们来说，这样做会容易得多。好的。是时候让你也这么做了
I'll see you in the next lecture.
我将在下一节课上见到你。
[music]
[音乐]